Fares Farah, Information Technology Major

Information Technology Assistant | York University

Toronto, ON | 647.400.7254 | faresfarah 2003@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/fares-farah

Professional Summary

Knowledgeable, business savvy, strategic thinker, with demonstrated success in the technological, musical, and business fields. Highly effective leader, with diverse experience across multiple areas including Information Technology, teaching, managing, and performing.

Key Skills

- Excellent Customer Service
- Calendar Management
- Strong Communication Skills
- Willingness to Keep Learning
- Excellent organizational skills
- Ability to Learn Autonomously
- Time management skills
- Detail-oriented
- Manage Ticketing System

Work Experience

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY ASSISTANT | York University | Toronto, ON | 2023-Present

- Managing the inventory and deployment part of our ticketing system and database for York University devices through HaloTSM ticket system and Microsoft Excel
- Helping with setting up desktop and laptop computer systems around the York University campus for students, professors, and York University staff
- Responsible for providing network, software application, and project-related support
- Managing, storing and organising the equipment in our back room for easy deployments

COMPUTING SUPPORT ASSISTANT | York University | Toronto, ON | 2021-2023

- Provide emergency support to teachers who encounter challenges with computer systems before, during, or after their lectures
- Troubleshooting computer setups in classrooms and lecture halls making sure all audio, visual, internet and cloud file systems are in working condition
- Autonomously checking hundreds of rooms and their computer setups when no emergency help is required, making sure all technical aspects, that a professor would need to use, are in working condition

Education

Bachelor's in Information Technology | York University | Toronto, ON | 2021-Present OSSD Graduated with Honours | Earl Haig Secondary School | Toronto, ON | 2017-2021

Technical Skills

Windows | MacOS | MS Teams | O365 | Excel | HaloTSM | MS SCCM | ServiceNow | Active Directory | Zoom